字幕翻译制作：goodliuwu
第   六   感
冷起来了
It's gettin' cold.
这是个精美的相框
That is one fine frame.
精美的相框
One fine frame that is.
值多少...
How much...
这么精美的相框，你觉得呢？
Does a fine frame like that cost, do you think?
我没跟你说过，可你喝醉时说话有点像瑟斯博士美国著名儿童作家
I never told you, but you sound a little like Dr. Seuss when you're drunk.
我知道，我是认真问的
I know. I'm serious.
我也是认真的
Serious, I am.
我得说价值最少得几百
I'd say it cost at least a couple hundred.
我要给你读一下
I'm gonna read it for you.
我说话真的像瑟斯博士吗？
Do I really sound like Dr. Seuss?
“为表彰他在儿童心理学领域之杰出成就
"In recognition of his outstanding achievement in the field of child psychology."
“他对工作的尽心尽力，以及他持续致力于提高生活品质...
His dedication to his work and his continuing efforts to improve the quality of life..."
你专心点好吗？
Will you concentrate?
“他持续致力于提高生活品质...
"...his continuing efforts to improve the quality of life...
“为了无数儿童及其家人
"for countless children and their families,
“费城市府荣幸颁予费城之子
"the city of Philadelphia proudly bestows upon its son...
“马尔科姆·克劳医生” 就是你
Dr. Malcolm Crowe..." That's you...
“优异专业市长嘉奖”
"...the Mayor's Citation for professional excellence."
他们称你为费城之子呢
They called you their son.
我们该把它挂到卫生间去
We should hang it in the bathroom.
这对我们是重要的一晚
This is an important night for us.
终于，有人认识到你所做的牺牲
Finally, someone is recognizing the sacrifices you've made...
你把什么都放在第二位，包括我
that you have put everything second, including me,
只为了他们所说的那些家庭
for those families that they're talking about.
这也说明我丈夫有天份
They're also saying that my husband has a gift.
你有天分，教导孩子们...
You have a gift that teaches children...
如何坚强面对，连多数成人都会尿裤子的处境
how to be strong in situations... Where most adults would piss on themselves.
我相信他们写的是真的
I believe what they wrote is real.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我想用玻璃杯盛些酒
I would like some wine in a glass.
我不想盛在马克杯里
I would not like it in a mug.
我不想盛在罐子里
I would not like it in a jug.
看
Look.
安娜，不要动，不要出一点声
Anna, don't move. Don't make a sound.
这里是罗克斯街47号
This is 47 Locus Street.
你打破了一扇窗户，闯入私人住宅
You've broken a window and entered a private residence.
你不知道太多事情
You don't know so many things.
这所房子里没有针头或任何类型的处方药物
There are no needles or prescription drugs of any kind in this house.
你知道你独处时为什么会害怕吗？
Do you know why you're afraid when you're alone?
我知道 我知道
I do. I do.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
他许诺我的，我想要他许诺我的东西
What he promised me! I want what he promised me.
哦，我的天
Oh, my God.
我认识你吗？
Do I know you?
你不认识我吗，英雄？
Don't you know me, hero?
你连自己的病人都不记得了？
Don't you even remember your own patients?
市区诊所
Downtown clinic.
单亲家庭
Single-parent family.
可能有情绪障碍
Possible mood disorder.
我那时害怕
I was afraid!
你告诉我，我在处理父母离婚上有问题
You told me I was having trouble coping with my parents'divorce.
你错了 你错了
You were wrong. You were wrong.
现在看看我
Now look at me!
- 我再也不想要害怕  - 给我一分钟想想
- I don't want to be afraid no more. - Just give me a minute to think.
我等了你十年
I waited ten years for you!
我什么也不给你了
I'm not giving you nothin'!
本·弗里德金？
Ben Friedkin?
有些人，他们叫我怪胎
Some people, they call me "freak."
赖安·萨姆纳?
Ryan Sumner?
我就是，我就是个怪胎，瞧瞧我
I am. I am a freak. Look at...
文森特
Vincent.
文森特·格雷
Vincent Gray.
不，你不要
No, you don't.
我的确记得你
I do remember you.
安静，非常聪明
Quiet, very smart.
有同情心
Compassionate.
不同寻常的同情心
Unusually compassionate.
你忘了说“受诅咒的”
You forgot cursed.
你没治好我
You failed me.
你没治好我!
You failed me!
文森特，很抱歉如果我不是...
Vincent, I'm sorry if I wasn't...
如果我没帮到你
if I didn't help you.
但要是你能...让我试试
But if you just let me try,
要是你能给我一个机会
if you just give me a chance...
噢，上帝啊
Oh, God! Oh, God!
- 文森特有没有...  - 别说话，嘘
- Did Vincent... - Don't talk. Shh.
次年秋天
南费城
文森特·格雷，年龄 10
接诊  1989年1月19日
父母状况——离异
科尔·希尔  9岁
接诊 1998年9月
父母离异
极度焦虑
社交孤立
可能有情绪障碍
没事的，科尔
It's okay, Cole.
我是马尔科姆·克劳医生
My name is Dr. Malcolm Crowe.
我们今天本来要见面的，但是...
We were supposed to meet today, but...
我错过了咱们的预约
I missed our appointment.
对不起
I'm sorry.
知道吗，过去在欧洲，人们曾经躲进教堂
You know, in the olden days in Europe, people used to hide out in churches.
他们会要求避难
They would claim sanctuary.
他们在躲什么？
What were they hiding from?
躲坏人，多数情况下
Bad people, mostly.
那些人想把他们关进监狱，伤害他们
People that wanted to put them in jail, hurt them.
我注意到你的眼镜，上面并没有镜片
I noticed your eyeglasses. They don't have any lenses in them.
这是我爸的
They're my dad's.
镜片让我眼睛不舒服
The lenses hurt my eyes.
我进来的时候你在跟你的士兵们说什么？
What were you talking about with your soldiers when I came in?
“得...”
Day...
De profundus clamo adite domine
这叫拉丁语
It's called "Latin."
- 你的士兵们都说拉丁语吗？ - 不
- All your soldiers speak Latin? - No.
只有一个
Just one.
你是好医生吗？
Are you a good doctor?
哦
Well
我曾经是
I used to be.
我有一次得过一张奖状，市长颁发的
I won an award once from the mayor.
它的框很贵
It had an expensive frame.
我会再见到你，对吧？
I'm gonna see you again, right?
如果你觉得可以的话
If that's okay with you.
我回来了
It's me.
拉丁字典
主啊
我自深渊向你哭喊
嘿，早上好
Hey, good morning.
科尔
Cole.
Cole!
嘿，你的巧克力脆片都软掉了
Hey, your Cocoa Puffs are gettin' soggy.
让我看看你
Let me see you.
哦，亲爱的，你这儿有污点，抬头
Let me see you. Oh, honey, you got a spot. Head up.
好了，可以了
Okay, here we go.
你在找什么吗，宝贝？
Something you were looking for, baby?
夹心馅饼？
Pop Tarts?
就在这儿
They're right here.
你在想什么，妈妈？
Well, what are you thinking, Mama?
很多事
Lots of things.
有关我的不是？
Anything bad about me?
嘿，看着我的脸
Hey, look at my face.
我没在想你的不是
I was not thinking something bad about you.
明白吗？
Got it?
明白
Got it.
来，抬起头
Here, head up.
- 那是汤米  - 好了，你把它塞进去 科尔
- That's Tommy. - That's okay. You tuck it in.
科尔，你要这个吗？
Cole, you want this?
嘿，怪胎，你觉得搭肩膀那招如何？
Hey, freak, how'd you like that "arm around the shoulder" bit?
我刚装出来的，我发挥了一下
I just made that up. I went with it.
好演员都这么做，这叫即兴表演
It's what great actors do. It's called "improv."
嘿，宝贝
Hey, baby.
你今天怎么样？
How was your day?
你知道的，需要的话你可以跟我讲讲的
You know, you can tell me things if you need to.
你知道我今天做什么了吗？
Well, you know what I did today?
我...早上赢了宾州彩票
I, uh, I won the Pennsylvania Lottery in the morning,
我辞掉了我那些工作
I quit my jobs,
接着我去公园大野餐，吃了好多巧克力慕斯派
and I ate a big picnic in the park with lots of chocolate mousse pie.
然后我整个下午在喷泉里游泳
And then I swam in the fountain all afternoon.
你做了什么？
What'd you do?
我被第一个选入课间球队
I was picked first for kick ball teams at recess.
我打了支满垒全垒打赢下比赛
I hit a grand slam to win the game.
大家把我举在肩上，扛着我绕圈，欢呼
Everybody lifted me up on their shoulders and carried me around, cheering.
哦，那样的话，我要给你做些三角煎饼
Well, in that case, I am gonna make you some triangle pancakes.
给你一个钟头
You got an hour.
嗨
Hi.
想坐吗？
Wanna sit?
今天不想谈吗？
Don't feel like talking today?
想玩个游戏吗？
Wanna play a game?
这是个读心游戏
It's a mind-reading game.
是这样玩的
Here's how it works.
我来读你的心
I read your mind.
如果我说对了，你就朝椅子走一步
If what I say is right, you take one step towards the chair.
如果我说错了，你就后退一步，朝门口
If what I say is wrong, you take one step back... towards the doorway.
如果你走到椅子旁，就坐下
If you reach the chair, you sit down.
如果你退到门口，就可以走
If you reach the door, you can go.
想玩吗？
Wanna play?
好
Okay.
你母亲和父亲刚离婚时
When your mother and father were first divorced,
你妈妈去看过我这种医生，可他帮不了她
your mom went to see a doctor like me, and he didn't help her.
所以你觉得我也不能帮你
So you think I'm not going to be able to help you.
你担心 她说她跟医生说了一些事
You're worried that she said she told him things...
一些她不能跟其他人说的事
things she couldn't tell anyone else.
一些秘密
Secrets.
你有一个秘密，但你不想告诉我
You have a secret, but you don't want to tell me.
你爸爸走之前把那只表给你作礼物
Your dad gave you that watch as a present just before he went away.
他把它忘在抽屉里了
He forgot it in a drawer.
坏了
Doesn't work.
你在学校一直很安静，但...
You keep pretty quiet in school, but...
你是个好学生，你从没真正惹过什么大麻烦
you're a good student, you've never really been in any serious trouble.
有一次我们要画一幅画
We were supposed to draw a picture.
想画什么都行
Anything we wanted.
我画了一个人
I drew a man.
他脖子受伤了，另一个人用螺丝刀干的
He got hurt in the neck by another man with a screwdriver.
你在电视上看到的吗，科尔？
You saw that on TV, Cole?
人人都很不安
Everyone got upset.
他们开了个会
They had a meeting.
妈妈开始哭
Mom started crying.
我再也不那样画了
I don't draw like that anymore.
你现在怎么画呢？
How do you draw now?
我画…人们在微笑
I draw... people smiling,
狗在奔跑
dogs running,
彩虹
rainbows.
他们不会为了彩虹开会
They don't have meetings about rainbows.
没错，我想是不会
No. I guess they don't.
我现在在想什么?
What am I thinking now?
我不知道你在想什么
I don't know what you're thinking now.
我在想...
I was thinking...
你人是好
you're nice,
可你帮不了我
but you can't help me.
我以为你说的是另一家意大利餐厅，我向你求婚那家
I thought you meant the other Italian restaurant I asked you to marry me in.
对不起，安娜
I'm so sorry, Anna.
我好像就是掌握不好时间
I just can't seem to keep track of time.
而且今天的访谈也不太好
And I didn't have a very good session today.
他们俩多么相似
They're both so similar.
同样的小习惯，同样的表情，脑子里悬着同样的事情
The same mannerisms, same expressions, same things hanging over their head.
我想可能是某种虐待
I think it might be some kind of abuse.
科尔的手臂上有抓痕
Cole has... scratches on his arm.
我想可能是指甲抓伤
I think they might be fingernail cuts.
防卫伤，也许，我不知道
Defensive cuts, maybe. I don't know.
可能是个老师或邻居
Maybe a teacher or a neighbor.
我认为不是他母亲，我已见过她和他相处，看起来不符合
I don't think it's the mother. I've seen her with him, and it doesn't seem to fit.
也可能只是我搞错了
Or I could just be wrong.
也许他只是个很喜欢爬树的孩子
Maybe he's just a kid who likes to climb trees a lot.
安娜
Anna.
我知道我这段时间有点疏远，好吗
I know that I've been a little distant, all right?
我知道这让你生气，我只是...
I know that it makes you mad. I just...
觉得这像是给了我第二次机会，我不想让它溜走
feel like I'm being given a second chance, and I don't want it to slip away.
安娜
Anna.
结婚纪念日快乐
Happy anniversary.
别看着我
Stop looking at me.
我不喜欢人家这样看着我
I don't like when people look at me like that.
不错
Good.
我跟汤米·汤马西诺一起走这条路上学
I walk this way to school with Tommy Tammisimo.
他是你的好兄弟？
Is he your best buddy?
他讨厌我
He hates me.
你讨厌他吗？
Do you hate him?
不
No.
那是你妈妈安排的？
Did your mom set that up?
对
Yes.
你跟你妈妈谈过跟汤米相处的事吗？
Did you ever talk to your mom about how things are with Tommy?
- 我不跟她谈事  - 为什么？
- I don't tell her things. - Why not?
因为她没有像其他人那样看待我，我不想要她那样
'Cause she doesn't look at me like everybody else, and I don't want her to.
- 我不想让她知道  - 知道什么？
- I don't want her to know. - Know what?
知道我是个怪胎
That I'm a freak.
嘿
Hey.
你不是怪胎，好吗？
You are not a freak. Okay?
谁跟你这么说你都不要相信，那是屁话
Don't you believe anybody that tries to convince you of that. That's bullshit.
你一生里不必相信这种话
You don't have to go through your life believing that.
好吗？
Okay?
走吧
Come on.
- 你说了脏话  - 对，我知道 对不起
- You said the "S" word. - Yeah, I know. Sorry.
那么你爸爸是住在匹兹堡，和一位在收费站工作的女士
So your dad lives in Pittsburgh with a lady that works in a toll booth?
我想知道她工作时尿急怎么办？
I wonder if she has to pee when she's working.
你觉得她会忍着吗？
Think she just holds it?
我不知道，我也在想这问题
I don't know. I was just thinking about that myself.
今天你问了很多有关爸爸的问题
You asked a lot of questions about Dad today.
为什么？
How come?
这个...有时我们会做些事来引起注意
Well, sometimes we do things to draw attention,
以表达我们对特定问题的感觉
to express our feelings about certain issues...
离婚，诸如此类
divorce, whatever.
举个例子，一个人可能会把东西留在桌上，让别人找到
For example, a person might leave something on the desk for someone else to find.
你知道自由联想书写是什么吗，科尔？
Do you know what free association writing is, Cole?
不知道
No.
自由联想书写就是拿起一支笔
Free association writing is when you take a pencil in your hand, and
你把笔放在一张纸上，开始书写
you put the pencil to a piece of paper and you start writing.
你不去看或是想你在写什么
And you don't look at what you're writing or think about what you're writing.
你就是...让手不停地动
You just keep your hand moving.
过一阵子，只要你的手动得够久 ...
And after a while, if you keep your hand moving long enough,
一些词和想法就开始出现，你甚至不知道它们在你心里
words and thoughts start coming out that you didn't even know you had in you.
可能会是...你在别的地方听说的事
It could be something you heard somewhere else,
或是...藏在你内心深处的感觉
or feelings you had deep inside of you.
吓人的玻璃，哦不，上帝
不，什么鬼事？
让该死的婴儿安静
我会割你，我发誓
来人停止燃烧
我要杀了你
我要杀了你们全部杂种
你做过自由联想书写吗，科尔？
Have you ever done any free association writing, Cole?
写过
Yes.
你都写些什么?
What did you write?
不安的词语
Upset words.
在你爸离开前，你写过什么不安的词语吗？
Did you ever write any upset words before your father left?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
你能为我做件事吗？
Can you do something for me?
我要你想一下，你想要从咱们的访谈中得到什么结果
I want you to think about what you wanna get out of our time together...
咱们的目标应该是什么
what our goal should be.
某件我想要的东西？
Something I want?
如果你能改变你人生中的某件事，什么东西都行
If you could change something in your life, anything at all,
你会要什么？
what would it be?
不算我想要的，可不可以是我不想要的？
Instead of something I want, can it be something I don't want?
可以
Okay.
我不要再害怕
I don't want to be scared anymore.
探访者也必须认
知到，有虐待迹
象的孩子，其手
臂及腿上的伤痕
，事实上，可能
是自残。
探访者也必须认
知到，有虐待迹
象的孩子，其手
臂及腿上的伤痕
，事实上，可能
是自残。
你要去开门吗？
You gonna get that?
你去不去开门啊？
Are you gonna get that?
你在店里没看够我吗？
Don't you see enough of me at the store?
对，我正要去亚米希村的跳蚤市场
Yeah, I'm on my way out to the flea market in the Amish country.
我想也许你想一起去...
I thought maybe you'd wanna come along...
教教我怎么买那些东西
and show me how to buy at one of these things.
我不知道今天能不能对付亚米希人
I don't know if I can deal with the Amish today.
在他们旁边你不能骂脏话吐口水什么的
You can't curse or spit or anything around them.
我只是想着你可能想出去呼吸点空气
I just figured maybe you'd just want to get out and get some air,
因为最近你似乎有点低落
because you've seemed kind of down lately.
我没事
Um, I'm okay.
你觉得我回来时是不是过来一趟，给你看看我买的东西
Do you think that maybe I should stop by on the way back, show you what I got?
不会很麻烦的
Because that wouldn't be a problem.
不，我...我可以周一再看
No, l... You know, I can see on Monday.
当然，对，没关系，我只是...
Sure, yeah, that's fine. I'm just...
好的，那我就走了，回头再谈
Okay, so I guess I'm gonna get going then. I'll speak to you later.
- 别踩到马粪了  - 多谢你了
- Don't step in the horse manure. - Thank you very much.
继续走啊，臭小子
Keep moving, cheese dick.
我不会打人或踢人了
随笔：
费城在美国革命中的地位
谁能猜一猜
Can anybody guess...
1790到1800年间美利坚合众国的首都是哪里？
what city was capital of the United States of America from 1790 to 1800?
给你们一个提示：是你们住的城市
I'll give you a hint: It's the city you live in.
- 费城  - 对了
-Philadelphia! - Right, right.
费城是本国最古老的城市之一
Philadelphia's one of the oldest cities in this country.
许多代人在这里生活，在这里死去
A lot of generations have lived here and died here.
这城里你去的几乎每一个地方，背后都有历史和故事
Almost anyplace you go in this city has a history and a story behind it.
连这所学校和学校所在地也有
Even this school and the grounds it sits on.
有没有人猜一下，一百年前这栋建筑是做什么用的？
Can anyone guess what this building was used for a hundred years ago...
在你来上学之前，甚至在我来这儿上学之前
before you went to school here, before I went to this school even?
说吧，科尔
Yes, Cole.
他们以前在这儿吊死人
They used to hang people here.
不，这...不正确，你从哪儿听来的？
No, uh, that... Mm-mm. That's not correct. Where'd you hear that?
他们把人拉进来，犯人哭着跟亲人亲吻告别
They pulled the people in, crying and kissing their families bye.
人们看着...向他们吐口水
People watching... spit at them.
科尔，这栋房子以前是座法院
Uh, Cole, this building was a legal courthouse.
法律在这里通过，其中一些是本国最早的法律
Laws were passed here... some of the very first laws of this country.
整座房子满是律师，立法者
This whole building was full of, uh, lawyers, lawmakers.
他们就是吊死大家的那些人
They were the ones that hanged everybody.
我不知道这些同学中谁跟你说的，不过...
I don't know which one of these guys told you that, but, uh,
他们只是想吓唬你
they were just trying to scare you.
我不喜欢别人这样看我
I don't like people looking at me like that.
怎样看你？
Like what?
别看了
Stop it!
我...我...我不知道还能怎么看
I, uh, l-l-I don't know how else to look.
你是结巴斯坦利
You're Stuttering Stanley!
什么？
Excuse me?
你在这里上学时说话很可笑，你直到高中说话都可笑
You talked funny when you went to school here. You talked funny all the way to high school.
- 什么？  - 你不该盯着别人，这样会让对方难受
- What?  - You shouldn't look at people. It makes them feel bad.
- 你怎么... - 别再看着我了
- How did you... - Stop looking at me!
你跟谁...跟谁聊过？
Who have you... Been speaking to?
结巴斯坦利 结巴斯坦利...
Stuttering Stanley! Stuttering Stanley!
- 别说了  - 结巴斯坦利
- Stop it. St-St-St... - Stuttering Stanley!
- Stop that! - Stuttering Stanley! Stuttering Stanley!
结巴斯坦利...
Stuttering Stanley! Stuttering Stanley!
住嘴，你...你这怪胎
Shut up, you f-f-freak!
嘿 大佬
Hey, big guy.
怎么了？
How's it goin'?
我现在什么都不想谈
I don't wanna talk about anything right now.
好吧
Okay.
你喜欢魔术吗?
You like magic?
看好：魔术硬币
Observe: The magic penny.
看起来像是普通硬币
Looks like an ordinary penny.
但我来个魔术摇一摇
But I do my little magic shake, and...
现在它在我右手里
now it's in my right hand.
但这还没结束把戏
But that's not the end of the magic trick.
我再摇一下
I do another little shake, and...
就在背心口袋里
right there in the vest pocket.
但这还没结束把戏
But that's not the end of the magic trick.
我再摇一下
I do another little shake...
然后
and...
正好回到一开始的左手里
right back in the left hand where it started.
这不是魔术
That isn't magic.
说什么呢？这当然是魔术
What are you talking about? Of course it's magic.
你一直把硬币留在那只手里
You just kept the penny in that hand the whole time.
这样啊？
Think so?
我不知道你会搞笑
I didn't know you were funny.
马尔科姆，你那帅屁股坐下来听好了
Malcolm, sit your cute butt down and listen up.
不容置疑，安娜就像我的姐妹
No doubt about it. Anna is like my sister.
你最好让她快乐，我说的可不是...
And you better make her happy. I'm not talkin'about no...
不是“呣，这奶油味道真好”那种快乐
"Mmm, this taste like real butter"kind of happy.
我说的是...怎么了，姑娘？
I'm talkin' about... What's up, girl?
朱莉·安德鲁丝，在山顶上像个精神病人跳舞一样那么快乐《音乐之声》
"Julie Andrews twirling around like a mental patient on a mountaintop" kind of happy.
我说的是这种快乐
That's the kind of happy I'm talkin'about.
嘘，过来
Shh. Come here.
嘘，别跟她说是我说的
Shh. Don't tell her I told you,
她说过第一次在街上遇见你，她就知道她爱你
but she said she knew she love you from the first time she met you on the street.
她愿意为你做任何事
She'd do anything for you.
我爱你们
I love you guys.
我鼻涕直流，关掉...
My nose is running. Turn it...
(左洛复 抗忧郁剂 与食物或牛奶同服)
然后来个魔术一摇
And then you do the magic shake.
硬币就从我口袋...
The penny has moved from my pocket...
一路回到开始的手里
all the way back to the hand it started in.
真蠢
That's stupid.
这本来应该很好笑的
It's supposed to be funny.
太蠢了
It's stupid.
把硬币还我
I want my penny back.
他很少被邀请，这是我们的荣幸
He doesn't get invited places, so it's our pleasure.
上次是一次查克芝士儿童快餐厅趴，一年前了
Last time was a Chuck E. Cheese party a year ago.
他躲在一个紫色塑料管子里不肯出来
He hid in one of those purple plastic tunnels and didn't come out.
- 查克什么？  - 芝士，是个小孩去的地方
- Chucky who? - Cheese. It's a kids place.
- 借过  - 抱歉
- Excuse me. - Sorry.
外面有人吗?
Is someone out there?
请打开这扇门
Open this door, please. Come on.
我喘不上气了，要是你听见了就开门吧
I can't breathe. If you can hear me, open this door.
我以性命起誓，我没偷主人的马
I swear on my life I didn't take the master's horse.
打开这扇门，否则我破门而出来抓你
Open this door, or I'll break through it and grab you!
- 广告明星都有自己的拖车  - 干嘛用？
- The star of the commercial always gets his own trailer. - For what?
他得有个地方思考角色，一个人
He needs a place to think about his character, alone.
你只有一句台词
You only had one line.
德里克，来看看
Derrick, check it out.
哦，是啊，我爸逼我邀请他的
Oh, yeah. My dad made me invite him.
生日快乐 德里克
Happy birthday, Derrick.
里面有什么东西你想看吗？
Is there somethin' you want to see in there?
没有
No.
我们要玩一个扮演剧
We're gonna put on a pretend play.
想加入吗？
Wanna be in it?
好
Okay.
就叫做《锁入地牢》
It's called "Locked in the Dungeon."
对，科尔，你就扮演那个锁入地牢的
Yes, Cole, and, uh, you get to be the one locked in the dungeon.
不要，不要
Don't! Don't! Don't! Don't!
不要...
Don't!
让我出去，不...
Let me out! No! No!
不！不！
No! No!
科尔？
Cole?
科尔
Cole!
这门有钥匙吗？
Is there a key for this door?
科尔？亲爱的，听得见我吗？
Cole? Honey? Honey, can you hear me?
科尔...天啊!
Oh, my God! Cole!
救救我！救命！救命！
Help me! Help! Help! Help!
多项检查显示他没有癫痫症状
The tests would indicate he did not have a seizure.
他很好
He's doing fine.
休息一下，他今晚就可以回家了
After some rest, he can go home tonight.
这位是导演希亚马兰，时年27岁
有些割伤和擦伤在你儿子身上
There's some cuts and bruises on your son...
- 令我担心  - 糟了
- that are concerning me. - Oh, man.
对，那是运动造成的
Yeah, those are from sports.
你认为是我伤害我的孩子？
You think I hurt my child?
你认为我是个坏母亲？
You think I'm a bad mother?
那边的斯隆太太，她是医院的社工
Mrs. Sloan over there, she's a social worker with the hospital.
她会问你一些程序上的问题
She's gonna ask you a couple procedural questions.
我的孩子今天出了什么事？
What happened to my child today?
有事发生在他身上，确实发生了，很糟糕的事
Something was happening to him, physically happening. Something was very wrong!
你父亲曾给你讲过睡前故事吗？
Did your father used to tell you bedtime stories?
很久以前有一个年轻的王子
Once upon a time there was this young prince,
他决定要开车兜风
and he decided that he wanted to go for a drive.
他找来他的司机，他们就开始出发
He got his driver, and they started driving.
开啊，开啊
Driving, driving.
开了很久，然后...
Driving a lot. And, uh,
他们开太久，他睡着了...
they drove so much that he fell asleep.
接着...
And...
等他醒来，他发现他们还在开车
Then he woke up, and he realized they were still driving.
- 这是段很长的旅程...  - 克劳医生?
- This was a very long trip. - Dr. Crowe?
你以前没讲过睡前故事
You haven't told bedtime stories before.
呃，是不太多，没说过
Uh, not too many, no.
你得加点转折什么的
You have to add some twists and stuff.
好，加点转折
Okay. Some twists.
比如哪种转折？给我个例子吧
Like what kind of twists? Give me an example.
也许他们没油了
Maybe they run out of gas.
他们没油了？这不错，他们在开车，对吧？
They run out of gas? That's good, 'cause they're driving, right?
好，那么...
Okay, so...
跟我说说你为什么哀伤的故事
Tell me the story about why you're sad.
你觉得我哀伤？
You think I'm sad?
你怎么会这么想？
What makes you think that?
你的眼睛告诉我的
Your eyes told me.
我不该谈这样的事情
Not supposed to talk about stuff like that.
很久以前，有一个人，名叫马尔科姆
Once upon a time, there was this person named Malcolm.
他跟孩子们一起工作
He worked with children.
他爱这工作
He loved it.
他爱这工作甚于一切
He loved it more than anything else.
后来有一天晚上，他发现自己...
And then one night, he found out that he made a...
对其中一个孩子犯了错误
mistake with one of them.
他帮不了那个孩子
He couldn't help that one.
他自责不已
And he can't stop thinking about it.
他...无法忘怀
He can't forget.
从那时起，事情都变了
Ever since then, things have been different.
他不再是以前那个人了
He's not the same person that he used to be.
而他的妻子...
And his wife...
不喜欢变了以后的这个人
doesn't like the person that he's become.
他们几乎不再交谈，就像陌生人
They barely speak anymore. They're like strangers.
后来有一天，马尔科姆遇见一个了不得的小男孩
And then one day, Malcolm meets this wonderful little boy.
一个很棒的小男孩
A really cool little boy.
让他想起另一个孩子的许多
Reminds him a lot of the other one.
马尔科姆决定试着去帮助这个新的男孩
And Malcolm decides to try and help this new boy...
因为他感觉如果能帮助这个新男孩
'cause he feels that if he can help this new boy,
那就像是...也帮助了另外那个
it will be like... helping that other one too.
这故事的结局如何？
How does the story end?
我不知道
I don't know.
现在我想告诉你我的秘密了
I wanna tell you my secret now.
好
Okay.
我能看见死人
I see dead people.
在梦里吗？
In your dreams?
在你醒着的时候？
While you're awake?
死人，就像是，在坟墓里的，棺材里的？
Dead people, like, in graves, in coffins?
像普通人一样走来走去
Walking around like regular people.
他们互相看不见
They don't see each other.
他们只看得见他们想看到的
They only see what they wanna see.
他们不知道自己已经死了
They don't know they're dead.
你多常见到他们？
How often do you see them?
时时刻刻
All the time.
他们无处不在
They're everywhere.
你不会跟别人说我的秘密，对吧？
You won't tell anyone my secret, right?
不会，我保证
No. I promise.
你能等我睡着再走吗？
Will you stay here until I fall asleep?
当然
Of course.
科尔...的病情比最初的评估更严重
Cole has pathologies more severe than initially assessed.
他受到幻觉困扰
He's suffering from visual hallucinations,
妄想症
paranoia,
某种学龄儿童的精神分裂症
Some kind of... school-age schizophrenia.
药物治疗，住院治疗，也许是需要的
Medication, hospitalization may be required.
我对他没有帮助
And I'm not helping him.
嗨，我是琳恩·希尔，科尔的妈妈
Hi, this is Lynn Sear, Cole's mom.
对，我想跟你谈谈...
Yeah, uh, l... I'd like to talk to you...
你儿子和他的朋友，别再碰我儿子...
about your boy and his friends keeping their goddamn hands off my son.
妈妈？
Mama?
不，晚饭还没好
No, dinner is not ready!
你要做什么？
What are you gonna do?
你再不能伤害我了
You can't hurt me anymore!
奈迪，你是个可怕的丈夫，奈迪！
Neddy! You're a terrible husband, Neddy!
看看你逼我干了什么，奈迪
Look what you made me do! Neddy!
从前有个男孩
Once there was a boy,
和其他男孩完全不同
very different from all the other boys.
他住在丛林里
He lived in the jungle,
他还能跟动物说话
and he could speak to the animals.
你觉得这出戏烂透了吗？
Did you think the play sucked big time?
什么？
What?
汤米·汤马西诺演过一个咳嗽药广告
Tommy Tammisimo acted in a cough syrup commercial.
他说大家都演得自觉而不实在
He said everyone was self-conscious and unrealistic.
他还说这出戏烂透了
He said the play sucked big time.
这个叫汤米的小孩好像很讨人厌
This Tommy kid sounds like a real punk.
我觉得这出戏很精彩，比《猫》还棒
I thought the play was excellent. Better than "Cats."
根据艾略特儿童诗改编的歌舞剧，深受欧美儿童喜爱
- 《猫》？  - 算了
- "Cats"? - Never mind.
科尔，我对你在医院里跟我说的话很感兴趣
Cole, I was really interested in what you told me at the hospital.
我想再多听一些
I'd like to hear more about it.
科尔？
Cole?
怎么了?
What?
那边有什么东西？
Is something up there?
科尔
Cole,
我什么也没看见
I don't see anything.
待着别动
Be real still.
有时你从内心感觉到
Sometimes you feel it inside,
好像你在快速下坠
like you're falling down real fast,
但其实你只是站着没动
but you're really just standing still.
你曾感觉过后脖梗发凉吗？
You ever feel the prickly things on the back of your neck?
有
Yes.
还有你胳膊上的汗毛，根根直立？
And the tiny hairs on your arm, you know, when they stand up?
有
Yes.
那就是他们
That's them.
当他们生气时
When they get mad,
就开始冷
it gets cold.
我没看到什么，你确定他们在那边吗？
I don't see anything. Are you sure they're there?
科尔
Cole?
请你叫他们走开
Please make them leave.
我正在努力
I'm workin' on it.
走吧
Come on.
妈妈，爸爸
Mommy, Daddy?
我的喉咙好疼
My throat hurts.
小儿止咳糖浆
Pedia Ease cough suppressant.
温和，快速，有效...
Gentle, fast, effect...
科尔
Cole.
我不管他们怎么说，这东西坏了
I don't care what they say, this thing is broken.
脱掉
Take 'em off.
我不要放在餐桌上
I don't want them on my table.
我打扫时看见你衣柜抽屉里有什么了
I saw what was in your bureau drawer when I was cleaning.
你要不要坦白一下？
Got something you want to confess?
那只大黄蜂链坠
The bumblebee pendant?
你为什么老是拿走它？
Why do you keep taking it?
那是外婆的
It was Grandma's.
你知道，万一摔坏了呢？你知道我会多难过
You know, what if it broke? You know how sad I'd be.
你会哭，因为你非常想念外婆
You'd cry 'cause you miss Grandma so much.
没错
That's right.
有时候，人们以为丢失了东西
Sometimes people think they lose things,
其实没有失去，只是被移走了
and they really didn't lose them... it just gets moved.
所以你移走了大黄蜂链坠吗？
So, did you move the bumblebee pendant?
不要生气
Don't get mad.
那么这次是谁移走的？
So, who moved it this time?
也许是别人进了咱们家，把大黄蜂链坠拿出我的衣柜
Maybe someone came in our house, took the bumblebee pendant out of my closet...
再好好放进你的抽屉里
and placed it nicely in your drawer.
也许是
Maybe.
老天，我很累了，科尔
God, I am so tired, Cole.
我身体累，我脑子也累
I'm tired in my body, I'm tired in my mind,
我的...心里也累了
I'm... tired in my heart.
我需要帮助
I need some help.
我不知道你注意到没有，咱们的小家状况并不太好
You know, I don't know if you noticed, but our little family isn't doing so good.
我是说，我一直在祷告
I mean, I've been praying,
可一定是我没祷告对
but I must not be praying right.
看来我们只能互相回应对方的祈祷
Looks like we're just gonna have to answer each other's prayers.
要是我们不能好好交流，我们就不可能做到
If we can't talk to each other, we're not gonna make it.
现在告诉我，宝贝，我不会生气的，宝贝
Now, tell me, baby. I won't get mad, honey.
你有没有拿大黄蜂链坠？
Did you take the bumblebee pendant?
没有
No.
你吃够多的烤牛肉了，你得离开餐桌了
You've had enough roast beef. You need to leave the table.
去！
Go!
嘿，过来
Hey, come on.
我给你看我爸藏枪的地方，来
I'll show you where my dad keeps his gun. Come on.
塞巴斯蒂安，过来
Sebastian, come on!
妈妈
Mama?
如果你不是特别生气
If you're not very mad,
我今晚能不能睡你床上？
can I sleep in your bed tonight?
看着我的脸
Look at my face.
我没有特别生气
I'm not very mad.
宝贝，你怎么在发抖？
Baby, why are you shaking?
科尔，怎么了?
Cole, what's wrong?
哦，上帝，求你告诉我
Oh, God, please tell me!
求求你
Oh, please.
这是爱德华时期的...
It's Edwardian
精工制作，矿式切割的碎钻和一颗真彩缅甸蓝宝石
beautifully worked with mine-cut diamonds and an actual color Burmese sapphire.
永恒久远
It's timeless.
你...
You, uh...
有没有普通一点的？
Got anything a little plainer?
普通点？
Plainer?
你想要个普通的钻戒来配你那普通的未婚妻，是这样吗？
You want a plain ring to go with your plain fiance? Is that how it is?
不是，宝贝，别会错了意思
No! Baby, don't get in a tissy.
你这么漂亮
Uh... You're so beautiful.
你本身就像一颗缅甸蓝宝石
You're like a Burmese sapphire all by yourself.
你不需要这些
You don't need all that.
你们为什么不试戴一下
Why don't you try it on...
看看你俩对它感觉如何？
and see how you both feel about it.
瞧，感觉怎么样？
There. How does that feel?
我认为这枚钻戒，传达出一种渴望
I think this piece, um, communicates a longing.
我想象那个曾经拥有它的女人
I imagine that the woman who owned it...
爱上了一个无法在一起的男人
loved a man that she couldn't be with.
她有卷发和栗色眼睛吗？
Did he have wavy hair and chestnut eyes?
嗯，我不知道，但...
Um, I don't know, but...
这店里很多首饰都能沟通
a lot of the pieces in this store communicate,
我认为你们应该选一件跟你交谈的
and I think you should choose a piece that speaks to you.
我想，也许当人们拥有过东西，在他们去世后
I think maybe when people own things and then they pass away,
他们的一部分会复印在那些东西上
a part of themselves gets printed on those things,
就像...像是指纹
like... like fingerprints.
我把它包起来
I'll just wrap it up.
你不需要一个有硕士文凭的伙计
You don't need a guy with a Master's.
你需要一个脖子比脑袋粗的摔角手
You need a wrestler with a neck larger than his head.
不，我需要一个有硕士文凭的摔角手
No, I need a wrestler with a Master's.
- 这是什么？  - 生日快乐
- What's this? - Happy birthday.
- 你送的？  - 嗯
- For me? - Mm-hmm.
这是本...初版书
It's a... first edition.
这太贵了
You know, this is too much.
不，从你的圣诞奖金里扣
No. Took it out of your Christmas bonus.
完美的礼物，安娜
It's perfect, Anna.
谢谢
Thanks.
所有东西里你最想要的是什么？
What do you want more than anything?
我不知道
I don't know.
我跟你说过我想要什么
I've told you what I want.
我知道我想要什么
I know what I want.
我想能够再跟我妻子交谈
I want to be able to talk to my wife again.
就跟我们以前那样交谈
The way we used to talk to each other.
就像世上没有别人，只有我们
Like there was no one else in the world except us.
你要怎么做？
How are you gonna do that?
我不能再当你的医生了
Can't be your doctor anymore.
我没有给自己家人足够的关心
I haven't paid enough attention to my family.
这样做就会出问题
Bad things happen when you do that.
你懂吗?
Do you understand?
- 我会转走你，我认识两个心理医生...  - 别放弃我
- I'm going to transfer you. I know two psychologists. - Don't fail me.
别放弃，你是唯一能帮助我的人，我知道
Don't give up. You're the only one who can help me, I know it.
我帮不了你
I can't help you.
你...你...
You...
有其他人能帮你
Someone else can help you.
你相信我，对吧？
You believe me, right?
克劳医生，你相信我的秘密，对吧？
Dr. Crowe, you believe my secret, right?
我不知道该怎么回答，科尔
I don't know how to answer that, Cole.
你怎么能帮我
How can you help me...
如果你不相信我？
if you don't believe me?
有些魔术是真的
Some magic's real.
你知道你独处时为什么会害怕吗？
Do you know why you're afraid when you're alone?
我知道 我知道
I do. I do.
我很抱歉，文森特，希望我没离开你太久
I'm sorry about that, Vincent. I hope I didn't leave you alone too long.
这里好冷
Whew. It's cold in here.
文森特，你为什么在哭？
Vincent, why are you crying?
你不会相信的
You won't believe.
我很抱歉，文森特，希望我没离开你太久
I'm sorry about that, Vincent. I hope I didn't leave you alone too long.
这里好冷
Whew. It's cold in here.
文森特...
Vincent...
这里好冷
Whew. It's cold in here.
不，知道吗？我也从来不喜欢他
Nah, you know what? I never liked him either.
我小时候，有一次验血
When I was a kid, I had this blood test done,
我把辣椒芝士薯条吐了女护士一身
and I threw up chili cheese fries all over this male nurse.
打扰了，里德医生在2线
Excuse me. Dr. Reed is on line two.
文森特，请原谅，我得接这个电话
Vincent, will you excuse me? I have to take this.
- 给我一分钟时间，好吗？  - 好的
-Just give me a minute, okay? -Okay
Yo no quiero morir
Yo no quiero morir.
噢，我的天
Oh, my God.
你一直在到处跑？
You been running around?
让你感觉好受些？
Make you feel better?
我喜欢到处跑，很好的锻炼
I like to run around. It's good exercise.
现在想问我问题吗？
Do you want to ask me questions now?
想当M连的准下士吗，陆战队第七师第三营
Want to be a lance corporal in Company "M, " Third Battalion, Seventh Marines?
我们刚被派到广南省越南
We're being dispatched into the Quang Nam province.
等等吧
Maybe later.
有事发生了，对吗？
Something happened, didn't it?
你很激动？
You wigging out?
是的，我想是吧
Yes. I think I am.
你知道“Yo no quiero morir”什么意思吗？
Do you know what "Yo no quiero morir" means?
西班牙语
It's Spanish.
意思是“我不想死”
It means "I don't want to die."
你认为那些鬼魂跟你说话是想要什么？
What do you think these ghosts want when they talk to you?
我要你想一想，科尔
I want you to think about it, Cole.
我要你仔细想一想
I want you to think about it really carefully.
你认为他们想要什么？
What do you think they want?
只要帮助
Just help.
对了，我也是这么想的
That's right. That's what I think too.
他们只想要帮助，连那些吓人的也是
They just want help, even the scary ones.
我想我可能知道一个办法，让他们走开
I think I might know a way to make them go away.
怎么做？
How?
听他们说
Listen to them.
万一他们不想要帮忙呢？
What if they don't want help?
万一他们就是生气，就是想伤害别人呢？
What if they're just angry and they just want to hurt somebody?
我认为事情不会是这样的
I don't think that's the way it works.
你怎么能确定？
How do you know for sure?
我不确定
I don't.
怎么回事？
What's happening?
走开
Go!
不准进入
你这是怎么了？
What's happening to you?
有人在伤害你？我要揍扁他们
Is someone hurting you? I'll kick their ass.
科尔，要是他们伤害你...
Cole, if they're hurting you...
妈妈 你睡吧
Mama, you sleep now.
不准进入
我现在觉得好多了
I'm feeling much better now.
你想告诉我什么事吗？
Do you want to tell me something?
她跑了很远的路来找我，对吧？
She came a long way to visit me, didn't she?
我想是的
I guess she did.
能拿杯水吗？
Can you get some water?
那是她妹妹
That's her sister.
你知道，我父亲得癌症时我就经历过了
You know, when I went through this with my father's cancer...
我都不能想象一个孩子卧床两年
I just can't imagine a child being in bed for two years.
看过多少医生？
How many... How many doctors?
- 我想有六个了 - 六个不同的医生？
- I think it was six. - Six different doctors?
我想是的
I think so, yes.
我刚听说...小的那个现在也病了
I just heard the, uh, little one is falling ill now.
愿上帝帮助他们
God help them.
别回家，好吗？
Don't go home, okay?
我绝对不会的
I definitely won't.
先生？
Mister?
打扰了，先生
Excuse me, mister.
你是琪拉的爸爸吗？
Are you Kyra's daddy?
这是给你的
It's for you.
她...她想告诉你一件事
Sh-She wanted to tell you something.
不，他来了，他正朝我走过来呢
Oh, no, here he comes. He's coming my way. Psst!
你想跳舞吗？
Would you like to dance?
哦，其实，我只是跟朋友一起来
Well, actually, I just came with my friends.
哦，那么，这样如何？
Oh, well, how about this?
我们先跳一下
We can dance for a little bit, and
要是你不喜欢我跳的，你可以踢我
if you don't like the way I dance, you can kick me.
呃，那好吧
Oh, okay then.
该吃午餐了，琪拉
It's time for lunch, Kyra.
- 我现在觉得好多了  - 太好了，宝贝
-I'm feeling much better now. - That's so great, honey.
你该吃饭了
It's time for your food.
我吃完以后可以出去玩吗？
Can I go outside if I eat this?
我不知道，你知道下午你就病得厉害
I don't know. You know how you get sick in the afternoons.
再说吧
We'll see.
别说吃起来很奇怪，你知道我不爱听这话
Don't say that it tastes funny. You know I don't like to hear that.
萨米的妈妈打过电话
Tami's mom called.
你一直让她病着
You were keeping her sick.
你喜欢它，她说过
You liked it, she said.
她保护着你
She looked out for you.
琪拉要回来了吗？
Is Kyra coming back?
再也不会了
Not anymore.
好，我觉得够了，妆化好了
Ya, I think that's enough. That's enough makeup.
好的
Okay.
- 他们在叫马僮了  - 我们得赶快了
- They're calling for the stable boy. - We have to hurry!
你...你刚刚跟谁说话？
Who, uh... Who were you talking to?
只是在练习台词
Just practicing my lines.
谢谢你给我这个角色，坎宁安先生
Thanks for giving me this part, Mr. Cunningham.
知道吗，我在这上学时，剧院这里发生过一次大火
You know, when I went to school here, there was a terrible fire in this section of the theater.
他们重建了整个地方
They rebuilt the whole thing.
对，我知道
Yeah, I know.
年轻的亚瑟王
只有心灵纯洁的人，才能拔出石中剑
Only he who is pure of heart can take the sword from the stone.
让那孩子试试
Let the boy try.
他是个马僮，跟在马后头清扫的
He is a stable boy. He cleans up after the horses.
安静，蠢村夫
Silence, village idiot.
让那孩子上前来
Let the boy step forward.
万岁，亚瑟王
Hail, King Arthur!
我觉得你真的演得很棒，科尔
I thought you were really great in the play, Cole.
- 真的？  - 是的
- Really? - Yeah.
知道吗，还有...
You know what else?
什么？
What?
我觉得汤米·汤马西诺烂透了
I thought Tommy Tammisimo sucked big time.
我有个办法让你跟你妻子说话
I got an idea how you can talk to your wife.
等她睡着了
Wait till she's asleep.
她就会听进你的话，不知不觉中
Then she'll listen to you and she won't even know it.
我不会再见到你了，是不是？
I'm not gonna see you anymore, am I?
我想我们要说的都说过了
I think we said everything we needed to say.
也许是时候和你更亲近的人说说了
Maybe it's time to say things to someone closer to you.
也许我们可以假装明天还要见面
Maybe we can pretend like we're gonna see each other tomorrow.
只是假装
Just for pretend.
好的
Okay.
我现在要走了
I'm gonna go now.
明天见，科尔
I'll see you tomorrow, Cole.
我没事，警官，我没事
I'm okay, Officer.I-I'm okay.
我不知道是怎么回事
I don't know what happened.
天啊，希望没有人受伤
Geez, I hope nobody got hurt.
你很安静
You're very quiet.
你在气我错过了演出，对吗？
You're mad I missed the play, aren't you?
我有两份工作，宝贝
I have two jobs, baby.
你知道对我们有多重要
You know how important they are for us.
要是能去，我愿付出所有
I'd give anything to have been there.
我现在准备好跟你交流了
I'm ready to communicate with you now.
交流？
Communicate?
告诉你我的秘密
Tell you my secrets.
是什么？
What is it?
你知道那边有事故吧？
You know the accident up there?
对
Yeah.
有人受伤了
Someone got hurt.
是吗？
They did?
一位女士
A lady.
她死了
She died.
天啊，怎么你能看见她？
Oh, my God. What, you can see her?
对
Yes.
她在哪里？
Where is she?
就站在我的车窗旁边
Standing next to my window.
科尔，你吓着我了
Cole, you're scaring me.
有时他们也吓着我
They scare me too sometimes.
他们？
They?
鬼魂
Ghosts.
你看得见鬼魂，科尔？
You see ghosts, Cole?
他们要我替他们做事
They want me to do things for them.
他们...他们跟你说话？
They... They talk to you?
他们叫你做事情？
They tell you to do things?
以前就是他们伤害我的
They're the ones that used to hurt me.
你在想什么，妈妈？
What are you thinking, Mama?
你认为我是怪胎？
You think I'm a freak?
看着我的脸
Look at my face.
我绝不会那么想你，永远不会
I would never think that about you. Ever.
- 懂了吗？  - 懂了
- Got it? - Got it.
容我想一想
Just let me think for a minute.
外婆跟你问好
Grandma says hi.
她说她很抱歉拿走了大黄蜂链坠
She says she's sorry for taking the bumblebee pendant.
她只是太喜欢它了
She just likes it a lot.
什么？
What?
外婆有时会来看我
Grandma comes to visit me sometimes.
科尔，这样很不对
Cole, that's very wrong.
外婆过世了，这你知道
Grandma's gone, you know that.
我知道
I know.
- 她要我告诉你...  - 科尔，请别说了
- She wanted me to tell you... - Cole, please stop.
她要我告诉你，她去看你跳舞了
She wanted me to tell you she saw you dance.
她说，你小的时候...
She said when you were little,
你跟她吵过一次架
you and her had a fight...
就在你的独舞表演之前
right before your dance recital.
你以为她没来看你跳舞
You thought she didn't come to see you dance.
她看了
She did.
她躲在后面，那样你就看不见她
She hid in the back so you wouldn't see.
她...她说你就像个天使
Sh-She said you were like an angel.
她说...
She said...
你曾来到埋葬她的地方
you came to the place where they buried her,
问了她一个问题
asked her a question.
她说，答案是...
She said the answer is...
每一天
every day.
你问了她什么？
What did you ask?
我...
Do...
我有没有令她骄傲？
Do I make her proud?
妈妈
Mama.
大家好，正如你们多数人都知道的，我...
Hi, everybody. As most of you know, I...
我并不习惯讲话
I'm not used to doing this,
而且，我答应过安娜不会让她受窘
and I promised Anna that I'd try not to embarrass her.
这任务就交给她母亲吧
I'll leave that to her mother.
不过，我们的确要感谢你们大家到来
But we do want to thank all of you for coming...
并与我们分享这美妙的日子
and for sharing this wonderful day with us.
对我几乎是苦乐交加，因为我不想把她交出去
It's bittersweet almost, for me, 'cause I hate giving her up.
安娜
Anna?
我想你
I miss you.
我也想你
I miss you too.
为什么，马尔科姆？
Why, Malcolm?
什么？
What?
- 什么事...  - 你为何离开我？
- What is it? - Why did you leave me?
我没有离开你
I didn't leave you.
我看见的人
I see people.
他们不知道自己死了
They don't know they're dead.
你多常见到他们？
How often do you see them?
时时刻刻
All the time.
他们无处不在
They're everywhere.
他们只看得到他们想看的
They only see what they want to see.
好吧，麦克
Okay, Mikey.
等等，给我一分钟
Come on. Give me a minute.
天啊
Oh, God.
- 不是很痛  - 让我看看
- It doesn't even hurt. - Let me see.
让我看看，把手拿开
Let me see. Put your hand...
天啊
Oh, God.
好了，好了
Okay.
我想我没事，真的，我觉得只是穿过去了
I think I'm okay. Really, I think it just went...went in and out.
现在连疼也不疼了
It doesn't even hurt anymore.
我想我现在可以走了
I think I can go now.
我只是需要做几件事
I just needed to do a couple things.
我需要帮助一个人
I needed to help someone.
我想我做到了
I think I did.
我还要告诉你一些事
And I needed to tell you something.
你从来不是第二位的
You were never second.
从来
Ever.
我爱你
I love you.
现在你睡吧
You sleep now.
到了早上一切都会不一样
Everything will be different in the morning.
晚安，马尔科姆
Good night, Malcolm.
晚安，亲爱的
Good night, sweetheart.
M·奈特·沙马兰作品